A Finding Aid to the Focus Gallery Records, 1963-1987, in the Archives of American Art AAA.focugall
Archives of American Art
Focus Gallery records
1963-1987
AAA.focugall
Archives of American Art
11.8 Linear feet
The records of San Francisco Focus Gallery measure 11.8 linear feet and date from 1963-1987. The bulk of the collection consists of exhibition files. There are also artists files, sales information, correspondence, and scattered records of the gallery’s companion bookshop.
Focus Gallery.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 8 series.
Series 1: Administrative Records, 1963-1985 (Box 1; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1966-1987 (Boxes 1-2; 1 linear foot)
Series 3: Exhibition Files, 1966-1985 (Boxes 2-10; 8.5 linear feet)
Series 4: Artists Files, 1966-1978 (Boxes 10-11; 0 .5 linear feet)
Series 5: Financial and Legal Files, 1966-1987 (Box 11; 0 .2 linear feet)
Series 6: Sales and Inventories, 1966-1987 (Box 11; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 7: Printed Materials, 1966-1987 (Boxes 11-12; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 8: Guest Books, 1966-1970, 1978-1985 (Boxes 12-13; 0.6 linear feet)
Biographical/Historical note
Focus Gallery was founded by Helen Head Johnson (1916-1989) in 1966 on Union Street in San Francisco. The gallery exhibited and sold primarily art photographs and other contemporary art.
Helen Head Johnston believed that photography deserved its own exhibition space. As stated in the gallery’s first press release, “in seeking to encourage print collecting it (the gallery) offers not only a show place but also a market place for photographers.” While retaining an emphasis on Bay Area photographers, the gallery's exhibitions soon became international in scope, featuring little known and well-established photographers through both solo and group exhibitions. With few exceptions, the gallery's policy was to feature an artist only once. To help keep the gallery going in its early days, Johnston started a bookshop mail-order business. At the time of its closing in August 1985, Focus Gallery was the longest continuously operating photography gallery in the country. The bookshop continued in another location for an additional two years.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Focus Gallery records were donated by the estate of owner Helen Johnston, care of Gerald O’Conner, executor.
Related Archival Materials note
Among the holding of the Archives of American Art is an untranscribed interview of Helen Johnston by Louise Katzman or Irene Borger in the collection Interviews of California Photographers 1981 Jun.-Nov.20.
Helen Johnston left her private photography collection to the de Saisset Museum, the Oakland Museum of California, and the San Francisco Museum of Modern Art.
Scope and Contents note
The records of San Francisco's Focus Gallery measure 11.8 linear feet and date from 1963-1987. The bulk of the collection consists of exhibition files. There are also artists files, sales information, correspondence, and scattered records of the gallery’s companion bookshop.
Exhibition files comprise the bulk of the collection and generally contain a wide range of materials including correspondence, short biographies, forms requesting artists’ background information, flyers, booklets, brochures, checklists, loan agreements, sales records, news releases, and photographs and negatives. Among the many photographers exhibited were Ansel Adams, Berenice Abbott, Bill Brandt, Wynn Bullock, Paul Caponigro, Imogen Cunningham, Judy Dater, Robert Heinecken, Eikoh Hosoe, Annie Leibovitz, Eliot Porter, Aaron Siskind, Jerry Uelsmann, and Brett Weston.
A relatively small amount of general business correspondence includes orders and payments for photographic prints, books, and magazine subscriptions, some personal notes, and requests for information about how to submit for exhibitions and for exhibition schedules. Correspondents include customers, photographers, publishers, law firms, museum, and colleges and universities. Correspondence from the founding year contains Johnston’s letters to various venues prominent in art photography, such as George Eastman House. There is also a letter to Ansel Adams requesting prints to sell or for a small opening exhibit.
Additional records include artists’ files; sales and inventory records containing print and bookshop inventories, general pricing information and receipts for photographs; and printed materials including flyers and brochures, bookshop catalogs and news releases. There are also scattered administrative records, including gallery history, a file on the Toren Gallery and five owner’s notebooks, as well as The Imogen Cunningham Trust files documenting Focus Gallery's interactions with the trust before and after Cunningham’s death regarding photographs printed and signed by her; financial and legal files; and guest books.
Documents in the collection that pre-date the founding of the gallery are found in the Toren Gallery file and a few of the exhibition files.
Abbott, Berenice, 1898-1991; Adams, Ansel, 1902-1984; Brandt, Bill; Bullock, Wynn; Caponigro, Paul, 1932-; Cunningham, Imogen, 1883-1976; Dater, Judy; George Eastman House; Heinecken, Robert, 1931-; Hosoe, Eikō, 1933; Johnston, Helen, 1916-1989; Leibovitz, Annie, 1949-; Porter, Eliot, 1901-; Siskind, Aaron; Torren Gallery.; Uelsmann, Jerry, 1934-; Weston, Brett; Art dealers--California--San Francisco; Art galleries, Commercial -- California -- San Francisco; Gallery owners -- local; Photographers--United States; Photographic art galleries--California--San Francisco; Photographs; Photography -- Exhibitions; Photography, Artistic; Visitors' books; Women photographers
- Administrative Records, 1963-1985; Series 1; 8 Folders Box 1
  Arrangement note
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  Scope and Contents note
  Administrative records contain a gallery history file, a chronology of exhibits, owner Helen Johnston’s notebooks, a folder on Toren Gallery (founded by Robert Toren and also located in San Francisco), Imogen Cunningham Trust files regarding orders and sales of personally printed and signed photographs, and a polices and procedures file. The gallery history contains notes, press releases, and clippings, including a five year anniversary interview with Helen Johnston. This folder also has photographs, contact sheets and negatives of Ms. Johnston and the gallery. It appears that Robert Toren was a personal friend of Helen Johnston and sometimes gave her recommendations for photographers and exhibitions.
  - Chronology, 1966-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Gallery History, 1966-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Imogen Cunningham Trust Correspondence, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Imogen Cunningham Trust Invoices, Consignment Argreements, Printed Materials, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Owner's Notebooks, 1966-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Policies and Proceedures, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Toren Gallery, 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1966-1987; Series 2; 1 linear foot Box 1-2
  Folders are arranged chronologically
  Contains general business correspondence between owner Helen Johnston and customers, photographers, publishers, law firms, museums, and colleges and universities; some with enclosures such as photographs and brochures. Topics covered include orders and payments, and inquiries about the gallery and its exhibits. Additional correspondence may be found in Series 3: Exhibition files and Series 4: Artists files.
  - General Correspondence, 1966-1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 9-32)
  - General Correspondence, 1978-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
- Exhibition files, 1966-1985; Series 3; 8.5 Linear feet Box 2-10
  Series 1 is arranged in two subseries, Subseries 3.1: Solo Exhibition files and Subseries 3.2: Group Exhibition files
  Exhibition files include flyers and brochures, biographical materials, news clippings, correspondence, and sample photographs, slides and negatives. They may also include information on exhibition layouts, lists of photographs to be included, and wall text. Among photographers exhibited were Ansel Adams, Wynn Bullock, Imogen Cunningham, Judy Dater, Aaron Siskind, Jerry Uelsmann, and Brett Weston. The file on Willard Worden (1868-1946) contains photocopies of his military service records dating from 1898 to 1946.
  - Solo Exhibition files, 1966-1985; Subseries 3.1; 4.9 Linear feet Boxes 2-7
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by photographer's last name.
    - Mikkel Aaland, "County Fair Portraits" (1984), 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Berenice Abbott "Retrospective" (1975), 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Ansel Adams (1971), 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 8-11)
    - Sister Adele "Counterpoint: Photomontages in Color" (1975) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Michael Alexander (1969), 1969, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - James Alinder (1970), 1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Don Gregory Anton "Dreams of Eyes" (1983) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Bill Arnold (1983), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Steven Arnold (1983), 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Lucy Ash "Photo Synthesis" (1981) (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Sid Avery (1982), 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - James Barker "The Lew and Flo Gardner Family" (1974) (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Thomas F. Barrow (1972), 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Ruth-Marion Baruch (1976) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Michael Beard (1979) (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Don Beatty (1968), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Paul Berger "Roots" (1969) (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Michael Bishop (1971), 1967 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Alfred Blaker (1973) (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Jeffrey Blankfort (1967) (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - John Bloom (1985), 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Dave Bohn (1976), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Bill Brandt (1974) (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - John Brock (1971), 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Lawrie Brown (1982), 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Peter Brown (1980) (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Peter Brown (1983), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Michael Bry (1969), 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Wynn Bullock "Retrospective" (1975), 1967-1975 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Wynn and Edna Bullock (1981), 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 38-40)
    - Shirley Burden (1968), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Jack Cakebread "Images of the Natural Scene" (1967), 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Morrie Camhi "The Farmworkers" (1972) (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Morrie Camhi (1983), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Paul Caponigro (1969), 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Paul Caponigro (1984), 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - J.S. Cartier (1985), 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Ed Cismondi "Portfolio 40" (1969), 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Lucien Clergue (1984) (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - William Clift (1979), 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Van Deren Coke (1972), 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - John Collier (1970), 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Steve Collins (1976), 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Linda Connor (1971) (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - George Craven (1971) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Leon Crowl (1980) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Imogen Cunningham (1973), 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Imogen Cunningham "After Ninety" (1977) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Imogen Cunningham "Imogen Cunningham, Selections by Judy Dater" (1980), 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Imogen Cunningham "The Photography of Imogen Cunningham A Centennial Selection" (1983) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Darryl J. Curran (1974), 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - William Current (1983) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Margo Davis (1973), 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Nicholas Dean (1968) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Michele Dearborn "Ballet Photographs" (1982), 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Mike De Castro (1977), 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - David Donoho (1967), 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Nell Dorr (1973), 1968-1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Allen Dutton (1971), 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - John Dunlop "Wall Street" (1974) (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Sam Ehrlich (1975) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Eliot Elisofon "The Nile" (1966) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Margaret Fabrizio (1976), 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Andree Ferris (1968 and 1979), 1967-1981 (Box 3, Folder 20-22)
    - Ralph Fertig (1971) (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Peter Fink, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Robert Fitch "Mine Eyes Have Seen...Martin Luther King" (1969) (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Christa Fleishmann "A Mark in Time" (1971) (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Shirley Fisher (1980), 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Franco Fontana "Color Landscapes" (1980), 1977-1981 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Flo Fox "Asphalt Garden" (1983), 1973-1983 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Abe Frajndlich (1978), 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Lee Friedlander (1971), 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Susan Friedman "A Separate Place" (1974) (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Janet Fries (1982), 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Jack Fulton "Directing Point" (1977), 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Paul Fusco (1969) (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Oliver Gagliani (1968) (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Stephen Gale "New York Impressions" (1969) (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Richard Garrod (1968) (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Ingeborg Gerdes (1978) (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Ralph Gibson (1972), 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Ruth Mayerson Gilbert "Sight Unseen" (1980), 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Jerry Gordon "Swimmers" (1982) (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Laura Gilpin "50 Print Restrospective" (1976), 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Ken Graves (1979) (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Phillippe Halsman (1982), 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Betty Hahn (1974), 1969-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - John Harding "The Siblings" (1976) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Michael Harris (1982) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Howard Harrison "The Tiger's Tail: Photographs of Social Change" (1972) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lynne Harrison (1969) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Sam Haskins (1982), 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - David Heath (1968), 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Robert Heinecken (1968), 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Arnold Henderson (1970) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Abigail Heyman (1976) (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Lewis Hine (1971), 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Hy Hirsh (1978), 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Leo Holub (1978), 1964-1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Eikoh Hosoe (1970), 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Philip Hyde (1969) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Scott Hyde (1973), 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Scott Hyde (1983), 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Joseph Jachna (1980), 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Chris Johnson (1983) (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Thomas Johnson (1979) (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Phillip T. Jones (1971) (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Pirkle Jones (1970), 1970-1981 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - J. Jullien (1981) (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Theo Jung (1970), 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Lisa Kanemoto (1983) (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - John Kouns (1985) (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - George Krause "Saints and Martyrs Series" (1981), 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Leslie Krims (1969), 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Vilem Kriz (1973), 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Gernot Kuehn "Photographs 1979-1983" (1983) (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - J.H. Lartigue (1973), 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Gerald Lang (1979) (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Ellen Land-Weber (1980), 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Ellen Landweber (1974), 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Victor Landweber (1976), 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Harry Lapow (1982) (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Pok Chi Lau (1980) (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Alma Lavenson (1981), 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Annie Leibovitz (1975), 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Bosworth Lemere (1967), 1966 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Lynn Lennon (1980), 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Ken Light (1983) (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Fred Lonidier (1976), 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Fred Lonidier (1980), 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Gregory A. MacGregor (1976) (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Allen MacWeeney (1968) (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Anthony Maine (1978), 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Jay Maisel (1972), 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Adal Maldonado (1973) (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Rose Mandel (1968) (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Margery Mann (1973), 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Sally Mann (1984) (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Eugene Meatyard (1972) (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Gerda Mathan (1982), 1981 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Robert May "Multiple Images" (1975), 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John Mercer (1976), 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Phiz Mezey (1983) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Duane Michals (1978), 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Allan Miller (1969) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Wayne Miller (1967), 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Roger Minick (1977), 1971-1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Lizette Model "Portfolio" (1975) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Alfred Monner (1968), 1961-1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Inge Morath (1978), 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Barbara Morgan (1972) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Ka Morias (1977), 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Hiro Moriyasu (1967) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - William Mortensen (1975), 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Douglas Muir (1984) (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Michael McLoughlin (1968) (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Helen Nestor (1983), 1983-1988 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Bea Nettles (1977), 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Beaumont Newhall (1982), 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Anne Noggle (1974), 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Don Norwalk (1970) (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Ted Orland (1977), 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Danuta Otfinowski (1980), 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Bill Owens (1976) (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Timo Tauno Pajunen (1978) (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Phil Palmer (1967) (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Ann Parker (1983) (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Olivia Parker (1979), 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Roi Partridge (1983) (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Mitchell Payne (1972) (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Martha Pearson (1979) (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Nata Piaskowski "Light and Form" (1977), 1967-1977 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Eliot Porter (1969), 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - James Powell (1970), 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Rosamond W. Purcell (1981), 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Edward Putzer (1978), 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Paul Raedeke (1984) (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Mary Randlett (1972), 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Lilo Raymond (1978), 1977-1983 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Eli Reed (1983) (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Dorothy Reich (1979), 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Linda Rich (1976), 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Jacob Riis (1980), 1976-1980 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Art Rogers (1981), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Willy Ronis (1982), 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Robert Schneider (1978), 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Medford Schwartz (1967) (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Tom Shuler (1979), 1970-1980 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Julia Siebel (1983), 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Aaron Siskind (1970) (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Neal Slavin (1972), 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Seymour Snaer (1981), 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Peter Stackpole (1968), 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Edward Steichen (1982), undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Stefanie Steinberg (1977) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Lou Stoumen (1982), 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Karl Struss (1979), 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Jack Stuler (1968), 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Henry Holmes Smith (1985), 1974-1985 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Elizabeth Sunday (1984) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Charles Swedlund (1977), circa 1973-1977 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Steve Szabo (1978), 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Jerry Takigawa (1982) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Jak Tanenbaum (1984) (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Reesa Tansey (1978), 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Brian Taylor (1985), 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Margaret Tenney (1975), 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Edmund Teske (1974), 1972 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Philip Trager (1977), 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Arthur Tress (1973), 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Karen Truax (1975), 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Kay Tucker (1978), 1974-1978 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Mark Tuschman (1980), 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Jerry Uelsmann (1968), 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Lloyd Ullberg (1967) (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - James Van DerZee (1975), 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - David Vestal (1972), 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Christian Vogt (1978), 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Todd Walker (1970), 1967-1970 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Helen Wallis (1978) (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Samuel Wang (1968), 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - William Washburn (1985) (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Carlton E. Watkins (1973), 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Don Werner (1967), 1967-1971 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Brett Weston (1969), 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Cole Weston (1981), 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Sister Noemi Weygant (1968), 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Minor White (1970) (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Steven Wilson (1968), 1963-1968 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Geoff Winningham (1980), 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Garry Winogrand (1970) (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Kelly Wise (1977), 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Diane Witlin (1972), 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Marion Post Wolcott (1979), 1978-1985 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Willard Worden (1977), 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Don Worth (1978), 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Nathan Zabarsky (1971) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Group Exhibiton files, 1966-1985; Subseries 3.2; 3.6 Linear feet Boxes 7-10
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by exhibition title.
    - Alumni Exhibitions, San Francisco Art Institute (1981), 1968-1981 (Box 7, Folder 2-4)
    - "American Music Festivals of 1969" (1970) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Art and Animals: A Reverence for Life" (1974) (Box 7, Folder 6-8)
    - "Author-Photographers of Norther California" (1970), 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
    - "Bay Area Photographers 1954-1979" (1980) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "The Chinese in San Franciso" (1980), 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - "Collector's Choice I" (1969), 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
    - "Collector's Choice II" (1974), 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - "Collector's Choice II" (1978), 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
    - "Columbia Faculty Show" (1974) (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - "Collecting Photography: A Personal Choice" (1977), 1976 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - "Contemporary Photography from Chile and Argentina" (1984), 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Thomas Cooper, Paul Hill and Raymond Moore, British Photography (1977), 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - "Creativity in the Commercial World" (1981) (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - "Critic's Choice" (1972), 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
    - Imogen Cunningham Photography Award (1981), 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 25-26)
    - "The Child: Three Perspectives" (1969), 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - "Decade" (1980), 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - "Decorating with Photographs" (1967) (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - "Directions '74" (1974), 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - "Dualities" (1983) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "Early Landscape and Wildlife Photographs of California and the West" (1973) (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - "Egypt, Tombs, Pyramids and Other Ancient Monuments" (1979), 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "Fashion Photography in the Bay Area" (1983), 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "First Light" (1975) (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - "Five Portfolios: American Roads" (1982), 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "Folsom Prison 1880-1910" (1974), 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - "Food Fatasies" (1982) (Box 8, Folder 10)